Are you trekking around Eastern Europe?
Is Bulgaria your main destination?
Then you really have to make a phone call to make reservations there.
First of all, I have to tell you, that you are really lucky in case you get a fairly clear connection with Bulgaria and you are not disconnected while talking.
Secondly, we have to admit, that the westernization hasn't brought much modernization to Bulgaria yet.
So, that's why they don't really have a developed phone system.
But all in all, first of all, the thing you have to do in order to call Bulgaria, is to determine what time it is in Bulgaria.
Bulgaria is two hours ahead of Greenwich mean time.
It means, that it is seven hours later in Bulgaria than it is on the east coast of the United States.
And, ten hours later than it is on the west coast of the United States.
What do you have to do?
It is really easy.
First of all, you have to dial the international access code, which is 011again.
Secondly, the country code of Bulgaria going to be follow this number, which is 359.
And thirdly, remove the zero from the city code and dial the remaining numbers.
And last but not least, you should dial the four to eight digits which remain, which is your personal phone number.